

#### NEW GRAD - INVESTMENT SERVICES ADMINISTRATOR - DATA MANAGEMENT OPERATIONS

49 Feint Dr, Ajax, ON, L1T 0E6, Canada

🛘 (647) 913-8011 | 🗷 dhanushga.lionel@ontariotechu.net | 🏕 www.dlionel.me | 🖸 DannyLionel | 🛅 DannyLionel

## **Summary**

Recent graduate in Software Engineering with experience and extensive education in software design and application development. Excellent written and verbal communication to vast audience in both technical and non-technical backgrounds. Fast learner with strong time management and multi-tasking skills. Strong work ethic in team or individual settings to drive project success and process efficiency. Strong troubleshooting and problem solving skills with an analytical mindset.

### Skills

Languages Python, R, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, PHP, Java, C++

Frameworks NodeJS, ReactJS

**Database** SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL)

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Lev-Co** Port Perry, Canada

Web Developer April. 2021 - Present

- · Spearhead SEO strategy with President, sales team, and back-end developer to increase traffic on Lev-co.com
- Increased SEO global rank by 2,376,749 in 3 months
- Optimized web pages in HTML5 and CSS with keywords to increase SEO rank
- Maintained and cleaned up database of over 17,000 emails in Excel
- Created email templates and campaigns using Mailchimp, Aweber, and Constant Contact
- Provide web support via email, phone, and other electronic communications

**DLMedia** Ajax, Canada

Web Developer Intern

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2020

- · Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for websites based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards
- Implemented website maintenance, content management, update and security resource tutorials to assist end-user training

# **Project**

### **Dementia Support Application**

Oshawa, Canada

CAPSTONE PROJECT FOR ONTARIO SHORES CENTER FOR MENTAL HEALTH SCIENCE

May. 2020

- Communicated and worked effectively in two separate teams to create an application to enhance Reminiscence Therapy for Dementia patients with administrative and standard purposes
- Built ML model to predict images shown to patients with 70 percent accuracy
- Tested, validated and refactored code to ensure proper functionality
- Managed team meetings and discussed project's goals and objectives
- Met with capstone supervisor weekly, and Ontario Shores stakeholders monthly, to provide detailed project reports and milestone updates

### **MyTrack (Vehicle Tracking System)**

Oshawa, Canada

DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS FINAL PROJECT

Dec. 2020

- Collaborated in a group of 4 to create a IoT Vehicle Tracking System with Android App interface
- Designed and developed Data Analysis Node that logs GPS coordinates to database, provides driving analysis on both hard acceleration and hard breaking, and emails users with report of stats
- Assisted with design and development of Data Synchronization Node which checks cloud database for crash, waits for server to come online, starts the synchronization process, and syncs with the database using timestamps
- Developed the project report and presentation to course instructor and TA's

## **Education**

#### **Ontario Tech University**

Oshawa, Canada

B.Eng. in Software Engineering Sep. 2016 - Apr. 2021

• Relevant Coursework: Web Programming, Mobile Application Development, Machine Learning and Data Mining, Database Management System, Distributed Systems, Advanced Operating Systems